<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Satan in Devil Rooms (+Fallen Angels)</name>
    <directory>satan in devil rooms</directory>
    <id>2732699827</id>
    <description>This mod was inspired by [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2497020375]Devil Statues Plus[/url] and [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1190390846]Bombable Devil Statue[/url].

There's a devil statue in each Devil Room. Now, sometimes it'll turn into a Satan fight. Once you defeat Satan, each devil deal item will cost a single point of damage rather than one or more heart containers.

Note: After you defeat Satan, The Lost will be able to take all items instead of being limited to just one.

Note: Paying the spike price will lock in your devil deals. You can still get to Angel Rooms via: sacrifice rooms, confessionals, book of virtues, duality, eucharist, act of contrition, and holy cards (see below).

Satan has been nerfed here a bit. The Leeches and The Fallen won't show up.
[list]
    [*]Basement: HP nerfed to 150. Foot stomps won't show up.
    [*]Caves: HP nerfed to 300. Foot stomps won't show up.
    [*]Depths: HP nerfed to 450. Foot stomps won't show up.
    [*]Womb and beyond: HP at normal 600. Foot stomps will show up.
[/list]

Satan can only show up if:
[list]
    [*]it's a 1x1 devil room with a single devil statue in the normal position
    [*]there aren't any other enemies
    [*]there's at least one devil deal item for sale
[/list]

You can choose to spawn a Holy Card after defeating Satan. If you've defeated Satan at least once in a Devil Room then Holy Cards will grant an additional effect.
[list]
    [*]In Devil Rooms, Holy Cards will give you an Act of Contrition item wisp. Act of Contrition gives you a 50/50 chance to get an Angel Room after taking a devil deal. It also gives a tears up, and reduces the penalty for taking red heart damage. Wisps can be lost due to damage so you'll need to protect it.
    [*]Outside of Devil Rooms, Holy Cards will give you a 10% Angel Room chance on the floor they're activated on. This means: if the angel/devil chance was 50/50 then the card will give you 55/45 odds in favor of Angel Rooms. It'll also give you 55/45 odds if the odds had been 0/100. It makes it 50/50 and then gives you the 10 point increase.
[/list]

Note: You can't use the temporary Holy Mantle effect to pay the spike price.

Note: If you don't like this addition to Holy Cards then leave the option turned off in MCM. It'll disable it completely.

If Satan doesn't show up then you can bomb the devil statue to fight the fallen forms of Uriel and Gabriel. By default, they'll drop key pieces like normal.

Note: You'll need to have unlocked secret 155 &quot;The Angels Await!!!&quot; by completing chapter 6 (chest/dark room) before the fallen angels will spawn.

Note: Taking the free key pieces will not lock in your devil deals.

Mod Config Menu can be used to control how often Satan shows up and what the fallen angels drop. You can also make the fallen angels a bit easier by nerfing their HP to that of their non-fallen variants.
[list]
    [*]Uriel: 450 -&gt; 400
    [*]Gabriel: 750 -&gt; 660
[/list]

The Uriel first option was removed. To make this behave consistently between Angel and Devil Rooms, I'd recommend grabbing the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2927760501]Uriel before Gabriel[/url] mod.</description>
    <version>1.23</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Rooms"/>
    <tag id="Bosses"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
